【翻译：Cyru1s / Halcyon】
让我们开始课程
all right let's get started
【翻译：Cyru1s / Halcyon】
本课程是 6.824 分布式系统
this is 6.824 distributed systems so
本节课我们从分布式系统的
I'd like to start with just a brief
整体概要开始讲起
explanation of what I think a
大家都知道本课程的核心是
distributed system is you know the core
一系列计算集群通过网络
of it is a set of cooperating computers
共同完成
that are communicating with each other
某一串连贯的任务
over networked to get some coherent task
因此，我们在本课程中
done and so the kinds of examples that
重点介绍的一些案例包括：
we'll be focusing on in this class are
大型网站的储存系统
things like storage for big websites or
大规模数据集运算，如 MapReduce
big data computations such as MapReduce
以及一些更为奇妙的技术
and also some what more exotic things
比如点对点的文件共享
like peer-to-peer file sharing so
这只是我们学习过程中的一些例子
they're all just examples the kinds of
我们同样会关注
case studies we'll look at and the
为何分布式计算之所以如此重要
reason why all this is important is that
是因为许多重要的基础设施
a lot of critical infrastructure out
都是在此基础上建立的
there is built out of distributed
他们都需要多台计算机
systems infrastructure that requires
或者说本质上是
more than one computer to get its job
多台物理隔离的计算机
done or it's sort of inherently needs to
共同完成自己的工作
be spread out physically so the reasons
以及为何人们要创建这种运算架构
why people build this stuff so first of
我会先介绍分布式系统
all before I even talk about distributed
也是提醒大家
systems sort of remind you that you know
在你设计一个系统时
if you're designing a system or designing
或者面对一个你需要解决的问题时
you need to solve some problem if you
你需要知道他是否可以在
can possibly solve it on a single
不需要分布式系统的单机上解决
computer you know without building a
如果可以那就应该用单机解决
distributed system you should do it that
因为很多的工作都可以在
way and there's many many jobs you can
一台计算机上完成
get done on a single computer and it's
这通常比分布式系统简单很多
always easier so distributed systems you
在选择使用分布式系统解决问题前
know you should try everything else
你需要充分尝试别的思路
before you try building distributed
因为分布式系统会让问题解决
systems because they're not they're not
变得复杂
simpler so the reason why people are
我们也会说是什么促使了人们
driven to use lots of cooperating
通过计算集群来达到
computers are they need to get
更高的计算性能
high-performance and the way to think
以及思考他们是如何实现
about that is they want to get achieve
并行管理大量CPU 大量内存
some sort of parallelism lots of CPUs
大量磁盘臂也在同时移动
lots of memories lots of disk arms
以及为何要在
moving in parallel another reason why
计算集群中处理
people build this stuff is to be able to
容错问题
tolerate faults
比如两台计算机运行
have two computers do the exact same
完全相同的任务
thing if one of them fails you can cut
以防在其中一台发生问题
over to the other one another is that
以及一些
some problems are just naturally spread
物理上的问题
out in space like you know you want to
比如你在用网银转账之类的操作
do interbank transfers of money or
我们假设
something well you know bank A has this
银行A在纽约有一台服务器
computer in New York City and Bank B as
银行B在伦敦有一台服务器
this computer in London you know you
这就需要一种
just have to have some way for them to
克服两个银行服务器之间
talk to each other and cooperate in
物理距离的
order to carry that out so there's some
通信方式
natural sort of physical reasons systems
这是一个不可避免
that are inherently physically
的空间问题
distributed for the final reason that
最后人们为了解决
people build this stuff is in order to
一些安全问题
achieve some sort of security goal so
比如有一些代码并不被信任
often by if there's some code you don't
但是你有需要和他进行交互
trust or you know you need to interact
这些代码不会立刻做出坏事
with somebody but you know they may not
或者说这些代码只是
be immediate malicious or maybe their
可能会有一些bug导致不被信任
code has bugs in it so you don't want to
你可能需要将代码
have to trust it you may want to split
分多处运行
up the computation so you know your
在你的计算机上
stuff runs over there and that computer
和我的计算机上都会运行
my stuff runs here on this computer and
两份代码需要通过
they only talk to each other to some
某个狭义的网络协议通信
sort of narrow narrowly defined network
我们可能会担心
protocol assuming we may be worried
这里的安全问题
about you know security and that's
我们把它分成更多的计算机
achieved by splitting things up into
就可能出现孤立的问题
multiple computers so that they can be
这门课我们会一直讨论
isolated the most of this course is
性能和容错
going to be about performance and fault
剩下两点我们会通过
tolerance although the other two often
对某些案例的研究
work themselves in by way of the sort of
来学习
constraints on the case studies that
下面我们来看
we're going to look at you know all
这些分布式系统的问题
these distributed systems so these
因为系统中存在很多部分
problems are because they have many
这些部分又在并发执行
parts and the parts execute concurrently
正因为有多台计算机
because there are multiple computers you
所以才会遇到并发编程
get all the problems that come up with
以及各种复杂交互
concurrent programming all the sort of
所带来的各种问题
complex interactions and we're
我们还要考虑一些时序问题
timing-dependent stuff and that's part
这让分布式系统这门课变得很难
of what makes distributed systems hard
另一个很难的问题是
another thing that makes distributed
你会有多个实例
systems hard is that because again you
再加上网络
have multiple pieces plus a network you
所以会遇到一些意想不到的报错
can have very unexpected failure
如果只有一台计算机
patterns that is if you have a single
通常它只会正常工作
computer it's usually the case either
或者可能会崩溃
computer works or maybe it crashes or
或者是电源有问题之类的
suffers a power failure or something but
工作或崩溃 这相对简单
it pretty much either works or doesn't
分布式系统却不是这样
work distributed systems made up of lots
因为多台计算机中
of computers you can have partial
可能会遇到一部分实例停止
failures that is some pieces stopped
导致的局部错误
working other people other pieces
但是其他部分依旧在正常运行
continue working or maybe the computers
或者这些计算机都在正常运行
are working but some part of the network
但是网络断了或者不稳定
is broken or unreliable so partial
局部错误也是使这门课
failures is another reason why
很难的原因之一
distributed systems are hard and a final
最后一点很难的问题是
reason why it's hard is that you know
人们设计分布式系统
them the original reason to build the
的根本原因是为了
distributed system is often to get
获得更高的性能
higher performance to get you know a
比如一千台计算机
thousand computers worth of performance
一千个磁盘臂达到的性能
or a thousand disk arms were the
但是实际上
performance but it's actually very
一千台机器到底有几千台性能
tricky to obtain that thousand X speed
是一个棘手的问题
up with a thousand computers there's
这有很多难点
often a lot of roadblocks thrown in your
人们倍加小心地设计
way so they often takes a bit of careful
实际的系统 让你觉得
design to make the system actually give
它的性能达到了你投入的预期
you the performance you feel you deserve
那么解决这些问题
so solving these problems of course
就是本课的全部
going to be all about you know
我想选择来上这门课
addressing these issues the reason to
来解决这些问题
take the course is because often the
是因为问题和解决方案
problems and the solutions are quite
在技术上都很有趣
just technically interesting they're
有些很难的问题
hard problems for some of these problems
有着很漂亮的解决方案
there's pretty good solutions known for
但是有些问题就没有那么好的
other problems they're not such great
解决方案
solutions now distributed systems are
分布式系统正在现实生活中被运用
used by a lot of real-world systems out
像很多大型网站
there like big websites often involved
他们把大量的计算机
you know vast numbers computers that are
放在一起作为分布式系统
you know put together as distributed
当我刚开始教这门课的时候
systems when I first started teaching
分布式系统还是一种
this course it was distributed systems
学术上的好奇尝试
were something of an academic curiosity
人们只是发现
you know people thought oh you know at a
有时需要一些小型扩容
small scale they were used sometimes and
并且预感在未来
people felt that oh someday they'd be
这可能很重要
might be important but now particularly
但是随着大型网站的兴起和推动
driven by the rise of giant websites
出现了大量的数据
that have you know vast amounts of data
和充满服务器的仓库
and entire warehouses full of computers
再过去的二十年中
distributed systems in the last
分布式系统已经是
twenty years have gotten to be very
计算架构中很重要的一部分
seriously important part of computing
这意味着
infrastructure this means that there's
大量的精力投入到
been a lot of attention paid to them a
解决相关问题的工作中
lot of problems have been solved but
但是同样有少数问题
there's still quite a few unsolved
没有被解决
problems so if you're a graduate student
如果你对这方面研究感兴趣
or you're interested in research there's
还有很多关于分布式系统的问题
a lot to you let a lot of problems yet
等着你去解决
to be solved in distributed systems that
你们可以关注相关研究
you could look into his research and
最后 如果你是一位热衷动手的同学
finally if you like building stuff this
这会是一门不错的课程
is a good class because it has a lab
因为他有一系列实验
sequence in which you'll construct some
你会编写出重点为高性能和容错的
fairly realistic distributed systems
相当真实的
focused on performance and fault
分布式系统
tolerance
所以你会有很多机会
so you've got a lot of practice building
去构建一个分布式系统
districts just building distributed
并且让他们正常工作
systems and making them work all right
好了 让我们在说技术内容之前
let me talk about course structure a bit
说一下课程结构
before I get started on real technical
你们可能是通过百度找到了
content you should be able to find the
这门课的网站
course website using Google and on the
网站上有一些实验作业
course website is the lab assignments
课程时间表 和一个Piazza（某国外课程论坛）页面链接
and course schedule and also link to a
你可以在那里发布问题并获得解答
Piazza page where you can post questions
课程主要的教学人员有
get answers the course staff I'm Robert
我 Robert Morris 会进行课堂授课
Morris I'll be giving the lectures I
也有四个助教
also have four TAs you guys want to stand
你们想站起来和大家打个招呼嘛
up and show your faces the TAs are
助教会重点解决实验问题
experts at in particular at doing the
在工作时间
solving the labs they'll be holding
他们也会在办公室解答
office hours so if you have questions
各位关于实验的问题
about the labs you can come you should
你可以去办公室或将课程相关问题
go to office hours or you could post
发到Piazza上
questions to Piazza the course has a
这门课有几个重要组成部分
couple of important components one is
一个是课堂授课
this lectures there's a paper for almost
几乎每节课都有论文阅读 以及两次考试
every lecture there's two exams
两次编程实验
there's the labs programming labs and
以及一个可选的期末大作业
there's an optional final project that
你可以用一个实验来代替它
you can do instead of one of the labs
授课内容会围绕分布式系统
the lectures will be about two big ideas
主要是上面两个问题（性能和容错）
in distributed systems they'll also be a
同样也有几堂课会说一些关于
couple of lectures that are more about
编程实验的内容
sort of lab programming stuff a lot of
许多课程我们以案例分析为
our lectures will be taken up by case
主要形式
studies a lot of the way that I sort of
我会在课前提供一些
try to bring out the content of
关于分布式系统的论文
distributed systems is by looking at
有些学术研究 也有一些工业界
papers some academics some written by
关于现实问题的
people in industry describing real
现实解决方案
solutions to real problems
授课内容会被录像
these lectures actually be videotaped
我希望课程可以上传到网络
and I'm hoping to post them online so
这样你们可以在别的地方
that you can so if you're not here or
观看授课视频
you want to review the lectures you'll
你们也可以回顾课程视频
be able to look at the videotape
这里的论文每周会发布一次
lectures the papers again there's one to
主要为学术研究中
read per week most of a research paper
的一些经典论文
some of them are classic papers like
比如像今天我希望你们阅读
today's paper which I hope some of you
关于MapReduce的论文 这篇论文很老
have read on MapReduce it's an old paper
但是这篇论文不论在学术界还是工业界
but it was the beginning of its spurred
都激发了巨大的
an enormous amount of interesting work
关于分布式系统的兴趣
both academic and in the real world so
有一些经典论文 也有一些最近发布的论文
some are classic and some are more
他们会讨论一些
recent papers sort of talking about more
最近人们关心的
up-to-date research what people are
最新研究成果
currently worried about and from the
我希望这些论文可以让弄清楚
papers we'll be hoping to tease out what
一些基本问题 比如研究者们有哪些想法
the basic problems are what ideas people
这可能会也可能不会
have had that might or might not be
对解决分布式系统的问题有用
useful in solving distributed system
我们有时会讨论这些论文中的
problems we'll be looking at sometimes
一些实施细节
in implementation details in some of
因为包括很多
these papers because a lot of this has
软件系统的实际组成
to do with actual construction of of
我们同样需要花一些时间
software based systems and we're also
去看对人们对系统的评价
going to spend a certain time looking at
人们是如何通过
evaluations people evaluating how fault
评估系统容错性
tolerant their systems by measuring them
评估系统性能
or people measuring how much performance
或者是否有性能提升
or whether they got performance
来评价这个系统
improvement at all so I'm hoping that
我希望你们可以在来到课堂之前
you'll read the papers before coming to
完成论文的阅读
class the lectures are maybe not going
如果没有提前阅读
to make as much sense if you haven't
课堂授课不一定有足够的时间
already read the lecture because there's
我们没有足够的时间来解释
not enough time to both explaining all
论文中的每一个概念
the content of the paper and have a sort
同时还要兼顾一些
of interesting reflection on what the
有趣的拓展
paper means on the class so you really
我认真的希望大家来
got to read the papers before I come
课堂之前阅读论文
into class and hopefully one of the
我也希望快速高效的读论文
things you'll learn in this class is how
会是这堂课的一个收获
to read a paper rapidly and efficiently
比如跳过一些
and skip over the parts that maybe
并不太重要的部分
aren't that important and sort of focus
而琢磨作者重要的想法
on teasing out the important ideas on
我们课程网站上每一个日程的链接
the website there's for every link to
都有一个思考问题
by the schedule there's a question that
你应该在读完每篇论文后
you should submit an answer for
回答这个问题
every paper I think the answers are due
最好在零点前提交
at midnight and we also ask that you
我们也需要你在网站上提出
submit a question you have about the
关于论文的一些问题
paper through the website in order both
也可以让我思考一下我对课程的准备
to give me something to think about as
如果我有时间
I'm preparing the lecture and if I have
我会至少通过电子邮件
time I'll try to answer at least a few
回答一部分问题
of the questions by email and the
这些问题和回答都需要
question and the answer for each paper
在零点前提交
due midnight the night before there's
有两次考试
two exams there's a midterm exam in
一次是随堂期中
class I think on the last class meeting
大概在春假前最后一节课
before spring break and there's a final
并且会在学期期末周
exam during final exam week at the end
迎来期末考试
of the semester the exams are going to
考试内容主要为论文和实验中的内容
focus mostly on papers and the labs and
这是我建议最好的准备方式
probably the best way to prepare for
当然参加课堂授课
them as well as attending lecture and
阅读论文
reading the papers a good way to prepare
应该是大家这20年
for the exams is to look at all exams we
准备期末考的好方法
have links to 20 years of old exams and
你们应该可以了解
solutions and so you look at those and
我会在考试中
sort of get a feel for what kind of
提出哪一类问题
questions that I like to ask and indeed
因为我们不可避免地会读到
because we read many of the same papers
一些重复的论文
inevitably I ask questions each year
会有一些类似的问题
that can't help but resemble questions
出现在历年的题目中
asked in previous years the labs there's
关于四次实验
four programming labs the first one of
第一次实验需要在下周五前完成
them is due Friday next week lab one is
这是一个简单的MapReduce实验
a simple MapReduce lab to implement your
根据你们在论文中读到的来写
own version of the paper they write
我们几分钟后会讨论
today in which I'll be discussing in a
这篇论文
few minutes
第二个实验使用Raft算法
lab 2 involves using a technique called
为了实现容错
raft in order to get fault tolerate in
这是一个理论上
order to sort of allow in theory allow
通过复制来让系统容错的算法
any system to be made fault tolerant by
这就是Raft算法
replicating it and having this raft
他管理复制
technique manage the replication and
管理一种自动剔除
manage sort of automatic cut over
有问题的副本服务器
if there's a fault if one of the
这个就是Raft算法的容错实验
replicated servers fails so this is raft for
在第三个实验中
fault tolerance in lab 3 you'll use your
你需要使用你的Raft算法实现
raft implementation in order to build a
来建立一个可以容错的KV服务器
fault tolerant key-value server it'll be
他可以完成复制并容错
replicated and fault tolerant in a lab 4
在第四个实验中你需要
you'll take your replicated key-value
把你写的KV服务器分发到
server and clone it into a number of
一系列的独立集群中
independent groups and you'll split the
这样你会切分你的KV存储系统
data in your key value storage system
通过这些独立的副本集群
across all of these individual
进行加速
replicated groups to get parallel
并行的对集群进行多个复制
speed-up by running multiple replicated
你同样需要负责
groups in parallel and you'll also be
不同服务期间
responsible for moving the various
许多数据块的移动
chunks of data between different servers
来让他们在运行过程中不损失
as they come and go without dropping any
任何的数据
balls so this is a what's often called a
我们通常把它叫做 分片式KV服务
sharded key value service sharding
分片是指我们将数据放到了
refers to splitting up the data
多个服务器上的多个分区
partitioning the data among multiple
来实现并行加速
servers in order to get parallel speed
如果你不想做实验四
up if you want instead of doing lab 4
你也可以选择你自己的项目
you can do a project of your own choice
如果你对分布式系统
and the idea here is if you have some
有一些自己的想法
idea for a distributed system you know
比如我们课堂上讨论到的
in the style of some of the distributed
某个类型的分布式系统
systems we talked about in the class if
或者说你有一些
you have your own idea that you want to
自己的追求
pursue and you like to build something
并且对这个想法进行评估
and measure whether it worked in order
看他们能不能正确运行
to explore your idea you can do a
你可以选择做这个项目
project and so for a project you'll pick
这个项目中你需要联系一些你的同学
some teammates because we require that
因为我们需要以2-3人的
projects are done in teams of two or
小组形式完成
three people so like some teammates and
其中有人需要把想法发给我
send your project idea to us and we'll
我来确定下是否合适
think about it and say yes or no and
或者是给你一些建议
maybe give you some advice and then if
如果我觉得合适
you go ahead and do if we say yes and
你也想做这个项目
you want to do a project you do that and
你就可以用它在本学期末
instead of lab 4 and it's due at the end
代替实验四
of the semester and you know you'll you
你需要做一些系统设计
should do some design work and build a
并构建一个真实的系统
real system and then in the last day of
在最后一节课前演示
class you'll demonstrate your system
同时需要交一个简短的
as well as handing in a short sort of
关于你如何构建它的书面报告
written report to us about what you
我会在课程网站上
built and I posted on the website some
提出一些或许对你们有帮助的
some ideas which might or may not be
大胆的想法
useful for you to sort of spur thoughts
关于你应该如何构建这个项目
about what projects you might build but
当然最好的项目应该是
really the best projects are one where
你自己有一个很好的想法
sort of you have a good idea for the
你需要选择一个
project and the idea is if you want to
和课程讨论内容
do a project you should choose an idea
相关的系统
that's sort of in the same vein as the
作为你的
systems that were talked about in this
项目
class
回到实验部分
okay back to labs the lab grade they
实验成绩会有一系列
we give you you hand in your lab code
针对你代码的测试构成
and we run some tests against it and
你的成绩就是在我们所有的测试中
your grade will based on how many
你通过了多少个
tests you pass we give you all the tests
我们会公开全部的测试数据
that we use those no hidden tests so if
如果你完成的实验
you implement the lab and it reliably
可靠的通过了全部测试
passes all the tests and chances are
全部通过很有可能的
good unless there's something funny
除非出现一些有趣的问题
going on which there sometimes is
一般来说
chances are good that if you your coop
只要你在运行时通过了全部测试
passes all the tests when you run it or
你提交给我们运行也会通过全部测试
pass all the tests when we run it and
这样就会得到满分
you'll get a full score full score so
希望你们不会有任何
hopefully there'll be no mystery about
关于实验的问题
what score you're likely to get on the
我需要提醒你的是
labs let me warn you that debugging
debug这些代码很耗时间
these labs can be time-consuming because
因为他们是分布式系统
they're distributed systems and a lot of
他们有很多并发和通信的问题
concurrency and communication sort of
可能发生一些奇怪而困难的错误
strange difficult to debug errors can
你们应该尽早开始实验
crop up so you really ought to start the
不要在提交实验的
labs early don't don't even have a lot
最后时刻还要
of trouble if you be elapsed to the last
处理很多麻烦
moment you got to start early if your
如果有对实验有问题
problems please come to the TAs office
可以在工作时间来到助教办公室
hours and please feel free to ask
你可以在Piazza上自由提问
questions about the labs on Piazza and
当然我也希望
indeed I hope if you know the answer
如果你知道一个问题的答案
that you'll answer people's questions on
你可以在Piazza回答别人的提问
Piazza as well all right any questions
还有什么关于课程的问题吗
about the mechanics of the course yes
你问了这些部分
so the question is what is how does how
在总成绩的占比是多少
do the different factor these things
我其实不记得了
factoring the grade I forget but it's
不过你在课程网站上
all on the it's on the website under
应该能找到答案
something I think though it's the labs
我想实验应该是占比最大的
are the single most important component
那我们开始 我们这门课是
okay all right so this is a course about
关于应用的基础设施的
about infrastructure for applications
所以即便课程中我们会
and so although this course there's
分开说一些
going to be a sort of split in the way I
不同的应用
talk about things between applications
别人 或者一些用户之类
which are sort of other people the
在这些基础设施上
customer somebody else writes but the
编写的应用
applications are going to use the
但是我们在本课程中
infrastructure that we're thinking about
应该关注的是这些基础设施
in this course and so the kinds of
这些基础设施可能会
infrastructure that tend to come up a
涉及许多储存 通信
lot our storage communication and
和计算问题
computation and we'll talk about systems
我们会讨论包含所有
that provide all three of these kinds of
这三个部分的基础设施
infrastructure the the storage it turns
但事实证明我们最关注的
out that storage is going to be the one
是储存部分
we focus most on because it's a very
这是一个定义明确并有用的抽象概念
well-defined and useful abstraction and
并且通常比较直白
usually fairly straightforward
人们对于如何构建和使用储存系统
abstraction so people know a lot about
how to build how to use and build
包括去构建一种
storage systems and how to build sort of
可复制容错的 高性能的分布式储存实例
replicated fault tolerant
high-performance distributed
我们还会讨论一些
implementations of storage we'll also
我们现在正在使用的计算系统
talk about some some of our computation
比如 MapReduce
systems like MapReduce for today is a
我们也会说一些
computation system and we will talk
关于通信的问题
about communications some but mostly
但是出发点是我们
from the point is a tool that we need to
建立分布式系统所用的工具
use to build distributed systems like
比如一台计算机可能
computers have to talk to each other
需要通过网络相互通信
over a network you know maybe you need
但是可能需要保证一定的可靠性
reliability or something and so we'll
所以我们会提到一点
talk a bit about what we're actually
实际上我们更多是
mostly consumers of communication if you
使用已有的通信方式
want to learn about communication
如果你想了解更多关于通信系统的问题
systems as sort of how they work that's
可以参与6.829的课程
more the topic of six eight two nine
因此对于储存和计算
so for storage and computation a lot of
很多学习目标都是
our goal is to be able to discover
需要研究一些抽象方法
abstractions where use of simplifying
比如如何简化这些
the interface to these storage and
分布式储存和计算基础设施的接口设计
computation distributed storage and
computation infrastructure so that it's
我们就能以此构建应用
easy to build applications on top of it
最重要的是
and what that really means is that we
我们希望通过构建这种抽象的接口
need to we'd like to be able to build
将这些分布式特性隐藏在整个系统内而不被用户感知
abstraction that hide the distributed
nature of these of these systems so the
这是个几乎无法完全实现的梦想
dream which is rarely fully achieved but
但是我们确实希望建立这样的
the dream would be to be able to build
一个看上去完全是非分布式系统的储存接口
an interface that looks to an
application is if it's a non-distributed
就像一个普通的文件系统
storage system just like a file system
或者是一个大家都已经熟知如何写代码
or something that everybody already
knows how to program and has a pretty
或者是一个大家都已经熟知如何写代码
simple model semantics we'd love to be
我们希望有一个看上去
able to build interfaces that look and
具有正常非分布式行为的
act just like non-distributed storage
文件系统和计算系统
and computation systems but are actually
但是实际上其中又有着
you know vast extremely high performance
极高的计算性能和容错的分布式系统
fault tolerant distributed systems
我们都需要建立这个抽象
underneath so we both have abstractions
但是随着课程进行
and you know as you'll see as a course
我们会知道
goes on we sort of you know only part of
很少有人能找到一个抽象
the way there it's rare that you find an
觉有这些分布式系统的
abstraction for a distributed version of
储存和计算特性
storage or computation that has simple
又有着非分布式系统一样
behavior behave just like the non just
人人都能理解的
non-distributed version of storage that
简单的行为
everybody understands but people getting
这方便我们还在尝试努力
better at this and we're gonna try to
课程中我们会学习人们在
study the ways and what people have
建立这些抽象的过程中做的努力
learned about building such abstractions
那么我们在考虑抽象时
ok so what kind of what kind of topics
首先需要看一个怎样的话题呢
show up is we're considering these
第一个话题
abstractions the first one this first
也是一个概括性话题
topic general topic that we'll see a lot
我们会看到的很多系统
a lot of the systems we looked at have
都和他们的实现有关
to do with implementation so for example
比如你看到很多人
the kind of tools that you see a lot for
在构建他们的系统时会用到
for ways people learn how to build these
类似远程过程调用（RPC）
systems are things like remote procedure
call
RPC 的目标就是
whose goal is to mask the fact that
试图掩盖我们正在
we're communicating over an unreliable
不可靠网络上通信的事实
network another kind of implementation
另一个我们会看到的实现是线程
topic that we'll see a lot is threads
这是一种编程技术
which are a programming technique that
让我们可以驾驭多核心计算机
allows us to harness what allows us to
harness multi-core computers but maybe
但是对于本课程而言 更重要的是
more important for this class threads
线程提供了一种结构化的并发操作方式
are a way of structuring concurrent
operations in a way that's hopefully
为的是简化程序员对这些
simplifies the programmer view of those
并发操作的视角
concurrent operations and because we're
因为我们会经常用到线程
gonna use threads a lot it turns out
我们知道
we're going to need to also you know
在实现这个层次上
just as from an implementation level
我们需要花费许多时间
spend a certain amount of time thinking
来思考并发控制
about concurrency control things like
比如锁
locks and the main place that these
关于这些实现思想会在课程中涉及
implementation ideas will come up in the
我们也会在许多论文里看到
class they'll be touched on in many of
但是你需要在实验里面对大多数这些问题
the papers but you're gonna come face
the face of all this in a big way in the
你需要构建分布式系统统
labs you need to build distributed you
如何进行分布式系统的编程
know do the programming for distributed
就像很多大家都知道的重要工具一样
system and these are like a lot of sort
of important tools you know beyond just
当然不是普通的编程
sort of ordinary programming these are
这是一些你构建分布式系统
some of the critical tools that you'll
需要使用的关键工具
need to use to build distributed systems
另一个重要主题
another big topic that comes up in all
很多论文里都会提到的：性能
the papers we're going to talk about is
构建分布式系统的更高目标
performance usually the high-level goal
是具有人们所谓的 可扩展的速度提升
of building a distributed system is to
get what people call scalable speed-up
我们正在努力提高可扩展性
so we're looking for scalability and
我这里说的可扩展性 和
what I mean by scalability or scalable
可扩展的速度提升 指的是
speed-up is that if I have some problem
如果我用一台计算机解决了一些问题
that I'm solving with one computer and I
当我买第二台计算机
buy a second computer to help me execute
去计算这个问题时
my problem if I can now solve the
只要一半的时间
problem in half the time or maybe solve
或者说比如说是每分钟内
twice as many problem instances you know
可以解决两倍数量的问题
per minute on two computers as I had on
两台计算机有两倍算力 就是我说的可扩展性
one then that's an example of
scalability so
（板书）2 x 计算资源数量
sort of two times you know computers or
可以得到两倍的性能 或者说吞吐量
resources gets me you know two times
performance or throughput and this is a
这是一个很强的工具
huge hammer if you can build a system
如果你真的构建了一个系统
that actually has this behavior named
只要提高几倍的机器的数量
that if you increase the number of
computers you throw at the problem by
系统就能同样提高几倍的性能或者吞吐量
some factor you get that factor more
throughput more performance out of the
这是一个巨大的胜利
system that's a huge win because you can
因为只要有钱就可以为所欲为买计算机
buy computers with just money right
就能达到这种效果
whereas if in order to get the
这种性能的提升
alternative to this is that in order to
否则就需要去给程序员
get more performance you have to pay
付钱去重构这些软件
programmers to restructure your software
来优化它的运行
to get better performance to make it
或者提供一些特殊的技术
more efficient or to apply some sort of
比如一个更好的算法之类
specialized techniques better algorithms
或者就要花高价雇程序员
or something if you have to pay
来修补这些代码
programmers to fix your code to be
从而提高运行速度
faster that's an expensive way to go
我们都希望比如从十台计算机
we'd love to be able just oh by thousand
提升到一千台计算机
computers instead of ten computers and
就能扛住一百倍的流量
get a hundred times more throughput
那这也太棒了
that's fantastic and so this sort of
因此当人们构建一个
scalability idea is a huge idea in the
巨大的购物网站的时候
backs of people's heads when they're
有一整栋楼的计算机在运行
like building things like big websites
他们共同完成网站的运行
that run on are you know building full
这是一个很棒的
of computers if the building full of
可扩展性的思路
computers is there to get a sort of
但是另一方面
corresponding amount of performance but
你需要仔细设计系统
you have to be careful about the design
才能获得这样的性能
in order to actually get that
呃 我在课程中可能会画图
performance so often the way this looks
比如我们来看这样一个图
when we're looking at diagrams or I'm
writing diagrams in this course is that
我们假设我们在
I'm supposing we're building a
建立一个常规网站
website ordinarily you might have a
一般来说一个网站有一个 HTTP 服务器
website that you know has a HTTP server
让我们先写一些用户
let's say it has some types of users
和很多浏览器
many web browsers and they talk to a web
他们在和一台web服务器通信
server running Python or PHP or whatever
比如是Python或者PHP写的服务
sort of web server and the web server
以及访问一些数据库
talks to some kind of database
网站只有一两个用户的时候
you know when you have one or two users
一台计算机就可以负担
you can just have one computer running
或者是一台跑web服务
both and maybe a computer for the web
一台跑数据库
server and a computer from the database
但是有可能你的网站
but maybe all of a sudden you get really
一夜之间火了起来
proper popular and you'll be up and
你发现可能有一亿人
you've you know 100 million people sign
注册你网站的账户
up your service ID how do you how do you
你怎么去维护你的网站
fix your site certainly can it support
一台机器承受一亿用户的流量不太可能
millions of people on a single computer
当然如果做了特殊的
except by extremely careful
劳动密集型优化除外
labor-intensive optimization but you
但很显然你没有那个时间
don't have time for so typically the way
所以你要做的第一件事情
you're going to speed things up the
就是购买更多的web服务器
first thing you do is buy more web
然后把不同用户分到不同机器上
servers and just split the user so that
一些用户或者特定的用户
you know how few users or some fraction
去访问第一台服务器
the user go to a web server 1 and the
另一半用户则去访问第二台
other half you send them to a web server
然而因为一些原因
2 and because maybe you're building I
比如你在建立reddit这种网站
don't know what reddit or something
所有的用户都需要
where all the users need to see the same
最终查看相同的数据
data ultimately you have all the web
你所有的web服务器都开始
servers talk to the backend and you can
和数据库通信
keep on adding web servers for a long
当然你可以一直加web服务器
time here and so this is a way of
提高后端代码并行效率
getting parallel speed up on the web
但是如果你是在跑
server code you know if you're running
PHP或Python代码
PHP or Python maybe it's not too
效率可能提高不了多少
efficient as long as each individual web
因为单台服务器没有提高多少效率
server doesn't put too much load on the
在数据库这里你也要
database you can add a lot of web
加同样多的机器避免问题
servers before you run into problems but
但是不幸的是
this kind of scalability is rarely
这种可扩展性很少是无限的
infinite unfortunately certainly not
without serious thought and so what
这个系统慢慢会变成
tends to happen with these systems is
你现在有了10台 20台 甚至100台web服务器
that at some point after you have 10 or
20 or 100 web servers all talking to the
都在和同一个数据库通信
same database now all of a sudden the
突然数据库这里成了瓶颈
database starts to be a bottleneck and
再加更多的web服务器也无济于事
adding more web servers no longer helps
所以很少有一个
so it's rare that you get full scale
你可以通过无限制添加服务器
ability to sort of infinite numbers of
就能完全解决扩展性的问题
adding infinite numbers of computers
随着你加了
some point you run out of gas because
越来越多的机器
the place at which you are adding more
机器本身的数量已经不是瓶颈了
computers is no longer the bottleneck by
因为你有了很多的web服务器
having lots and lots of web servers we
瓶颈转移到了别的地方
basically moved the bottleneck
我想是web服务器到数据库
I think it's limiting performance from
限制了性能
the web servers to the database and at
实际上你不可避免地
this point actually you almost certainly
要做一些架构设计
have to do a bit of design work because
因为很少有
it's rare that you can
这么直接的从一台数据库
there's any straightforward way to take
读数据的例子
a single database and sort of refactor
一台数据库你可以轻易排序
things with it or you can take data
但你需要重构
sort in a single database and refactor
把它分成多台数据库服务器
it so it's split over multiple databases
但这同样需要大量工作
but it's often a fair amount of work and
因为他很笨重
because it's awkward but people many
但是很多人确实需要这样做
people actually need to do this we're
我们在本课程中
gonna see a lot of examples in this
会看到很多例子
course in which the distributed system
人们讨论的一个分布式系统
people are talking about is a storage
是一个储存系统
system because the authors were running
因为作者在运行大型网站
you know something like a big website
并且单个服务器或者是
that ran out of gas on a single database
储存服务器都用光了
or storage servers anyway so the
于是这个扩展的故事是
scalability story is we love to build
我们希望可以这样简单的加钱买机器实现可扩展性
systems that scale this way but you know
但是这点很难实现
it's hard to make it or takes work off
于是这些设计工作
and design work to push this idea
其实会一直把这些想法推进下去
infinitely far ok so another big topic
另一个重要的话题是容错
that comes up a lot is fault tolerance
如果你建立了一个单机系统
if you're building a system with a
其实很好的使用单台计算机
single computer in it well a single
可以让他保持运行很多年
computer often can stay up for years
就像我办公室的服务器已经
like I have servers in my office that
运行了很多年而不会崩溃一样
have been up for years without crashing
电脑是可靠的
you know the computer is pretty reliable
操作系统是可靠的
the operating systems reliable
我办公室的电源也是可靠的
apparently the power in my building is
所以一台计算机
pretty reliable so it's not uncommon to
正常工作很长时间
have single computers it's just stay up for
是并不少见的
amazing amount of time however if you're
然而如果你建立了一个
building systems out of thousands of
数千台计算机组成的集群
computers then even if each computer can
那么即使每台计算机可以与一千台计算机一起运行一年
be expected to stay up for a year with a
thousand computers that means you're
这也意味着这一千台计算机中
going to have like about three computer
每天大约有3台计算机故障
failures per day in your set of a
所以大型分布式系统中的一个大问题是
thousand computers so solving big
problems with big distributed systems
我们把一个很罕见的错误
turns sort of very rare fault tolerance
very rare failure very rare failure
转变成了一个在一千台的
problems into failure problems that
分布式系统中
happen just all the time in a system
常见的错误
with a thousand computers there's almost
甚至在这种集群中
certainly always something broken it's
一直在发生的错误
always some computer that's either
总有一些机器会崩溃
crashed or mysteriously you know running
或者神秘地错误运行了
incorrectly or slowly or doing the wrong
或者卡顿 执行错误任务 之类
thing or maybe there's some piece of the
再有一千台计算机的网络中
network with a thousand computers we got
有许多的网络电缆
a lot of network cables and a lot of
许多的网络交换机
network switches and so you know there's
你要知道总有人会踩着电缆
always some network cable that somebody
所以这是不可靠的
stepped on and is unreliability or
或者网络电缆掉线了
network cable that fell out or some
或者某些交换机风扇坏了
networks switch whose fan is broken and
然后他们过热就不工作了
the switch overheated and failed there's
在你构建分布式系统的过程中
always some little problem somewhere in
各种地方总有一些小问题
your building sized distributed system
因此这个这个分布式系统的扩容
so big scale turns problems from very
把一个几乎不必要考虑的小问题
rare events you really don't have to
变成了一个持续不断的问题
worry about that much into just constant
这意味着对错误而言
problems that means the failure has to
正确回复 或者掩盖错误
be really or the response the masking of
以及继续处理的能力
failures the ability to proceed without
必须要在架构设计时就建立
failures just has to be built into the
因为错误总会发生
design because there's always failures
毕竟为应用开发者
and you know it's part of building you
提供方便的抽象接口
know convenient abstractions for
是我们真正要做的
application programmers we really need
但是我们需要构建
that but to be able to build
尽可能多的基础设施
infrastructure that as much as possible
才可能向应用开发者
hides the failures from application
隐藏和掩盖
programmers or masks them or something
这样每个应用开发者
so that every application programmer
就不需要一个复杂的代码
doesn't have to have a complete
来处理各种各样的
complicated story for all the different
类型的错误
kinds of failures that can occur there's
比如说容错到底指什么
a bunch of different notions that you
这会有一些不同的概念表述
can have about what it means to be fault
tolerant about a little more but you
但你应该明确的知道
know exactly what we mean by that we'll
尽管表述有很多
see a lot of a lot of different flavors
but among the more common ideas you see
有一个共同的思想就是可用性
one is availability so you know some
某些系统经过精心设计
systems are designed so that under some
以便在某种特定类型的错误下
kind certain kinds of failures not all
当然特定类型不可能是所有类型
failures but certain kinds of failures
系统可以正常运行
the system will keep operating despite
他们可以提供给你完整的服务
the failure while providing you know
undamaged service the same kind of
就像他们没有发生任何错误
service it would have provided even if
there had been no failure so some
某些系统的有这样一个可用的场景
systems are available in that sense that
你建立了冗余的服务
up and up you know so if you build a
比如说有两个备份
replicated service that maybe has two
即便一个备份发生了问题
copies you know one of the replicas
replica servers fail fails maybe the
可能另一个服务器还能正常运行
other server can continue operating
除非这两个都发生了错误
they both fail of course you can't you
我们不能在这个例子中
know you can't promise availability in
给出可用性的承诺
that case so available systems usually
我们的可用性都是建立在特定错误类型上的
say well under certain set of failures
we're going to continue providing
这样才能继续正常服务
service we're going to be available more
如果出现了超出范围的错误
failures than that occur it won't be
就不再可用了
available anymore
另一种容错
another kind of fault tolerance you
在除了可用性之外
might you might have or in addition to
他们自身的可恢复性也是一方面
availability or by itself as
recoverability and what this means is
这意味着如果出现问题
that if something goes wrong maybe the
他会停止工作
service will stop working that it is
他只是单纯的不响应请求了
it'll simply stop responding to requests
等到有人来进行修复后
and it will wait for someone to come
在修复完成后
along and repair or whatever went wrong
如果没有发生一些更糟糕的事情
but after the repair occurs the system
系统将可以继续正常运行
will be able to continue as if nothing
bad had gone wrong right so this is sort
这比可用性要弱一些
of a weaker requirement than
因为在出现故障的组件
availability because here we're not
被修复之前
going to do anything while while the
他不会做任何事情
failed come until the failed component
但是这一切都建立在没有损失正确性的前提下
has been repaired but the fact that we
can get up get going again without you
但是这一切都建立在没有损失正确性的前提下
know but without any loss of correctness
所以这仍然是一个重要的要求
is still a significant requirement it
对于一个可恢复的系统
means you know recoverable systems
你通常要在系统崩溃前做一些事情
typically need to do things like save
比如将最新日期存盘
their latest date on disk or something
才能在恢复后取回来
where they can get it back
比如供电恢复之后
you know after the power comes back up
对于一个高可用的系统
and even among available systems in
在实际生活中
order for a system to be useful in real
我们为了让一个系统好用
life usually what the way available
我们让系统保持可用
systems are aspect is that they're
直到一定量的错误发生
available until some number of failures
如果有太多的错误发生
have happened if too many failures have
这个系统就会停止工作
happened an available system will stop
或者停止对一切的响应
working or you know will stop responding
但是一旦足够的问题被修复
at all but when enough things have been
系统会继续工作
repaired it'll continue operating so a
所以一个好的高可用系统
good available system will sort of be
应该也是可恢复的
recoverable as well in a sensitive to
敏感的察觉发生了很多错误
many failures occur
然后停止响应
it'll stop answering but then will
但是在之后依旧正确工作
continue correctly after that so this is
我们很喜欢这一点
what we love - this is what we'd love to
我们会看到的最有效的工具是
obtain the biggest hammer what we'll see
解决这种问题的多种方法
a number of approaches to solving these
problems there's really sort of
实际上在这一部分中
things that are the most important tools
最重要的工具是
we have in this department one is
非易失性存储
non-volatile storage so that you know
一些类似于电源崩溃故障
something crash power fails or whatever
即便是整栋楼的电源故障
there's a building wide power failure we
我们可以用非易失性存储
can use non-volatile store it's like
像硬盘 闪存 SSD 之类的储存工具
hard drives or flash or solid-state
drives or something to sort of store a
我们存放一些检查点
check point or a log of the state of a
或者关于系统状态的日志
system and then when the power comes
在备用电源恢复或者故障修好了
back up or somebody repairs our power
我们得到通知可以去
suppliers notice what we'll be able to
读取最新的硬盘状态
read our latest state of the hard drive
并且继续从那里继续操作
and continue from there so so one tool
（板书）非易失性存储
is sort of non-volatile storage and the
于是出现了许多非易失性存储的管理工具
management of non-volatile storage just
comes up a lot because non-volatile
因为非易失性存储更新起来很昂贵
storage tends to be expensive to update
因此构建高性能容错系统非常繁琐
and so a huge amount of the sort of
nitty-gritty of building sort of
因此构建高性能容错系统非常繁琐
high-performance fault-tolerant systems
所以一个聪明的方法是
is in you know clever ways to avoid
避免写入非易失性存储
having to write the non-volatile storage
这在过去很常用
too much in the old days and even today
即便在今天 写入非易失性存储
you know what writing non-volatile
也需要移动磁盘臂
storage meant was moving a disk arm and
等待磁盘盘面旋转
waiting for a disk platter to rotate
这两个过程都很缓慢
both of which are agonizingly slow on
现在3GHz的微处理器
the scale of you know three gigahertz
即便已经在闪存读写上好了很多
microprocessors good things like flash
life is quite a bit better but still
即便已经在闪存读写上好了很多
依旧会遇到很多性能不够的情况
requires a lot of thought to get good
我们拥有的另一个重要的容错的工具
performance out of and the other big
tool we have for fault tolerance is
是复制
replication and the management of
复制的管理对你们可能有些棘手
replicated copies is sort of tricky you
任何一个复制系统中
know that sort of key problem looking in
都有一个非常关键的问题
any replicated system where we have two
比如我们有两台本应该有着
servers each with a supposedly identical
完全相同的副本的系统
copy of the system state the key problem
这个关键的问题就是
that comes up is always that the two
这两个副本总会意外的
replicas will accidentally drift out of
偏离同步的状态 不再正确
sync and will stop being replicas right
实际上对于任何一个设计
and this is just you know with the back
我们都能看到这种
of the every design that we're gonna see
通过使用复制实现的容错
for using replication to get fault
实验2就是一个
tolerance and in lab 2 you're all
通过管理管理复制实现的容错
about management management of
replicated copies for fault tolerance
你们会看到这非常复杂
as you'll see it's pretty complex
最后一个话题 也是一个跨领域的话题
final topic final cross-cutting topic is
是一致性
consistency so it's an example of what I
例如我们正在构建分布式存储系统
mean by consistency supposing we're
building a distributed storage system
假设这是一个键/值服务(KV服务)
and it's a key/value service so it just
它只支持两种操作
supports two operations maybe there's a
一个是「放入」(Put)
put operation and you give it a key and
提供一个key和一个value放入
a value and that the storage system sort
系统背后可能是一个
of stashes away the value under as the
通过一个大型的表之类
value for this key maintains it's just a
实现了这种操作
big table of keys and values and then
另一个是「取出」(Get)
there's a get operation you the client
你用客户端发送一个key
sends it a key and the storage service
储存服务找到这个key对应的value
is supposed to you know respond with the
作为返回值发回来
value of the value it has stored for
除了KV系统之外
that key right and this is kind of good
我很难找到把别的例子作为
when I can't think of anything else as
分布式系统的例子
an example of a distributed system all
这是一个还不错的例子
Oh without key value services and
这个例子也很实用
they're very useful right they're just
这可以算是一种
sort of a kind of fundamental simple
简单版本的储存系统
version of a storage system so of course
当然如果你是以为应用程序员
if you're an application programmer it's
如果对这两个操作有解释
helpful if these two operations kind of
是非常有帮助的
have meanings attached to them that you
你可以去查手册
can go look in the manual and the manual
手册会向你解释
says you know what it what it means what
以及你正确调用Get后
you'll get back if you call get right
它会返回什么
and sort of what it means for you to
以及正确的调用Put后 这很棒
call put all right so it'll be great there's
因为它们的含义对应着某种规范
some sort of spec for what they meant
没有这些关于Put/Get的描述
otherwise like who knows how can you
你又应该怎么写代码呢
possibly write an application without a
description of what putting get are
这就是我们关于一致性的话题
supposed to do and this is the topic of
以及为何这是一个
consistency and the reason why it's
在分布式系统中有趣的话题
interesting in distributed systems is
处于性能和容错两方面考虑
that both for performance and for fault
tolerant reasons fault tolerance reason
我们通常有多个数据副本
we often have more than one copy of the
data floating around so you know in a
所以在一个非分布式系统中
non-distributed system where you just
我们只有一台服务器一张表
have a single server with a single table
他们通常（虽然也不总是）
there's often although not always but
是没有相对而言没有歧义的
there's often like relatively no
当你做 Put Get 的时候
ambiguity about what put get could
一般就是正确的
possibly mean right in
你知道Put操作就是
to correctly you know what put means is
更新这个表
update the table and what get means is
Get操作就是从当前版本的表里取回值
just get me the version that's stored in
但是在分布式系统中
the table which but in a distributed
数据可能有超过一个副本
system where there's more than one copy
可能是因为复制或缓存的原因
in the data due to replication or
caching or who knows what there may be
于是有了很多个不同版本的KV对出现
lots of different versions of this key
value pair floating around like if one
如果其中有一个客户端
of the replicas you know if supposing
Put进了一个新的副本
some client issues a put and you know
在服务器就有了两个副本
there's two copies of the the server so
（板书）他们都有KV表
they both have a key value table right
比如两个表1对应的值是20
and maybe key one has value twenty on
both of them and then some client issues
这里有一个客户端
a put nice we have client over here and
他希望更新
it's gonna send a put it wants to update
把1对应的值改成了21
the value of one to be twenty-one all
比如这可能是一个计数器
right maybe it's counting stuff in this
于是他发送一个Put
key value server so sends a put with key
Key为1 Value为21
one and value twenty one it sends it to
他发送给了第一台服务器
the first server and it's about to send
他需要同步每一个副本
the same put you know wants to update
就在他正准备给第二台服务器
both copies right it keeps them in sync
发送同样的请求时
it's about to send this put but just
这个客户端崩溃了
before it sends to put to the second
可能是电源故障
server crashes I power failure or bug an
或者操作系统bug之类
operating system or something so now the
现在留下了一个不太好的状态
state were left in sadly is that we sent
我们发送的Put值更新了
this put and so we've updated one of the
两个副本中一个的状态
two replicas didn't have value twenty
一个是21 另一个仍是20
one but the other ones still with twenty
现在有人来尝试用一个Get来读取
now somebody comes along and reads with
他们想要得到Key为1对应的值
a get and they might get they want to
read the value associated with key one
他们可能得到了21或者20
they might get twenty one or they might
这取决于他们的请求
get twenty depending on who they talk to
发送到了哪个服务器
and even if the rule is you always talk
即便始终把第一台服务器放在首位
to the top server first if you're
我们构建容错系统时
building a fault-tolerant system the
实际规则应该是
actual rule has to be oh you talk to the
你先去请求第一台服务器
top server first unless it's failed in
遇到某些情况再请求下面这台
which case you talk to the bottom server
所以不管怎么说 你有总有一天
so either way someday you risk exposing
有风险遇到陈旧的数据副本
this stale copy of the data to some
很有可能的是
future again it could be that many gets
许多的Get都得到了21
get the updated twenty one and then like
但是比如下周突然有一个Get
next week all of a sudden some get
请求到了一周前的旧数据
yields you know a week old copy of the
这就会导致不一致
data so that's not very consistent
这显然是会发生的
right so in order but you know it's the
我们总会有不小心
kind of thing that could happen right
所以我们需要实际写下
we're not careful so you know we need to
关于Put和Get操作的一些规则
have we need to actually write down what
the rules are going to be about puts and
就像在这种危险的复制中
gets given this danger of due to
实际上
replication and it turns out there's
关于一致性的不同定义有很多
many different definitions you can have
许多听起来相对直白
of consistency you know many of them are
relatively straightforward many of them
比如我这里说的
sound like well I get yields the you
Put一定要是一个完整的Put
know value put by the most recently
这就是所谓的强一致性
completed put all right so that's
usually called strong consistency it
事实证明 构建一个
turns out also it's very useful to build
相对弱的一致性也很有用
systems that have much weaker
比如说
consistency there for example do not
我们不保证任何类似Get的操作
guarantee anything like a get sees the
可以看到最新的Put写入的值
value written by the most recent put and
（板书）强一致性
the reason so there's there strongly
consistent systems they usually have
是可以保证Get得到最新的Put的版本
some version that gets seen most recent
puts although you have to there's a lot
当然还有很多别的工作要做
of details to work out there's also
另一方面还有弱一致性
weakly consistent many sort of flavors
对于弱一致性系统
of weakly consistent systems that do not
他们不会做任何保证
make any such guarantee that you know
这些保证可能是
may guarantee well you're you know if
某个人做了Put
someone does a put then you may not see
你可能看不到这个Put的结果 而是旧的值
the put you may see old values that
weren't updated by the put for an
甚至可能在一个无限的时间里都是这样
unbounded amount of time maybe and the
人们之所以对弱一致性感兴趣
reason for people being very interested
人们之所以对弱一致性方案感兴趣
in weakly consistency schemes is that
因为强一致性虽然可以
strong consistency that is having these
让我看到的就是
actually I see be guaranteed to see the
保证是最新的值
most recent right that's a very
但是这个实现可能很昂贵
expensive spec to implement because what
因为这意味着
it means is almost certainly that you
总有部分需要做很多的通信
have to somebody has to do a lot of
来完成某一种强一致性概念的实现
communication in order to actually
implement some notion of strong
如果你有多个副本
consistency if you have multiple copies
这意味着不管是写入还是读取
it means that either the writer or the
都需要询问每一个副本
reader or maybe both has to consult
比如在我们的例子中
every copy like in this case where you
我们要知道客户端崩溃了
know maybe a client crash left one
更新了一个值 但另一个没更新
updated but not the other if we wanted
如果我们要实现强一致性
to implement strong
有一个简单的方法是
consistency see in them maybe a simple way
让客户端同时读取两个副本
in this system we'd have readers read
如果有一个更大一些
both of the copies or if there's more
那这个就是最新的值
than one copy all the copies and use the
我们这样就找到了
most recently written value that they
但这十分昂贵
find but that's expensive that's a lot
客户端要很多交流才得到一个值
of chitchat to read one value so in
所以为了尽可能地避免通信
order to avoid communication as much as
特别是副本隔得足够远
possible particularly if replicas are
人们会建立一个弱一致性系统
far away people build weak systems that
在这种情况下
might actually allow the stale read of
它实际上允许读取这个旧的值
an old value in this case although
当然为了让弱一致性更有用
there's often more semantics attached to
人们还会定义许多语义
that to try to make these weak schemes more useful
我们这里其实是一个通信问题
and we're this communication
强一致性需要更昂贵的通信
problem you know strong consistency
requiring expensive communication where
这会让人陷入麻烦
this really runs you into trouble is
如果我们把副本用于容错
that if we're using replication for
我们实际上希望他们可以
fault tolerance then we really want the
有着不同的故障概率
replicas to have independent failure
也就是不相关的故障
probability to have uncorrelated failure
比如
so for example putting both of the
把所有的副本放在同一个机房的
replicas of our data in the same rack in
同一个机架上
the same machine room it's probably a
这可能是一个糟糕的主意
really bad idea
因为如果有人绊倒了
because if someone trips over the power
那台机架的电源线
cable to that rack both of our copies of
我们的两个副本都会完蛋
our data are going to die because
因为它们都连接到同一
they're both attached to the same power
机架中的同一电源线上了
cable in the same rack so in the search
因此，为了使副本
for making replicas as independent and
尽可能独立且容错
failure as possible in order to get
以获得良好的容错能力
decent fault tolerance people would love
人们希望将不同的副本尽可能地分开远放
to put different replicas as far apart
例如放在不同的城市
as possible like in different cities or
或大陆的相对的两侧
maybe on opposite sides of the continent
这样，能摧毁一个数据中心的地震
so an earthquake that destroys one data
就极不可能
center will be extremely unlikely to
也摧毁另一个作为备份的数据中心
also destroy the other data center that
如大家所知，我们希望
as the other copy you know so we'd love
能够做到这一点，如果你这样做
to be able to do that if you do that
那么另一个副本是在数千
then the other copy is thousands of
英里开外
miles away and the rate at which light
按光传播的速度来算，它可能会耗费
travels means that it may take on the
几毫秒或几十毫秒
order of milliseconds or tens of
与横跨洲际的数据中心进行通信
milliseconds to communicate to a data
center across the continent in order to
只为更新数据的另一个副本
update the other copy of the data and so
这使得通信
that makes this the communication
需要强一致性和
required for strong consistency for good
高一致性，极可能非常耗时
consistency potentially extremely
就像每次你想要执行其中一项put操作一样
expensive like every time you want to do
one of these put operation
又或者取决于你如何实现它
or maybe again depending on how you
你可能必须坐在那里
implement it you might have to sit there
等待10或20或30毫秒
waiting for like 10 or 20 or 30
去同时通信到两个
milliseconds in order to talk to both
数据中心的副本，用来确保
copies of the data to ensure that
它们都已更新或已被检查
they're both updated or or both checked
以便获得最新的副本
to find the latest copy and that
那当然耗损巨大
tremendous expense right this is 10 or
这可是机器上的10或20或30毫秒
20 or 30 milliseconds on machines that
毕竟（用这些时间）我可以执行约十亿
after all I'll execute like a billion
每秒的指令数，故而我们浪费了
instructions per second so we're wasting
过多的潜在可执行指令
a lot of potential instructions while we
在我们等待人们用比较差的系统时
wait people often go much weaker systems
你只能更新
you're allowed to only update the
仅向你轮询的
nearest copy you're only consulted
最近的副本，我的意思是
nearest copy I mean there's a huge sort
现实世界的很多学术研究
of amount of academic and real-world
都在研究如何构建
research on how to structure weak
弱一致性保证，那样他们
consistency guarantees so they're
对应用程序才真正有用，以及如何
actually useful to applications and how
利用它们来
to take advantage of them in order to
实质性获得高性能
actually get high performance alright so
这些就是本课程中技术思想的快速预览
that's a lightning preview of the
technical ideas in the course any
有没有对刚才所讲的内容不懂的
questions about this before I start
在我讲MapReduce之前，好吧
talking about MapReduce all right I want
我想切换到MapReduce（的内容）
to switch to MapReduce that's a sort of
主要是详细案例研究
detailed case study that's actually
这些案例实际上会阐明
going to illustrate most of the ideas
我们现在在这里所讲内容的大部分思想
that we've been talking about here now
现在有一个系统
produces a system that was originally
该系统由Google 设计，构造和使用
designed and built and used by Google I
我认为这篇论文可以追溯到2004年
think the paper dates back to 2004 the
那时他们面临的问题是
problem they were faced with was that
他们要在TB级的数据上进行大量计算
they were running huge computations on
terabytes and terabytes of data like
比如创建所有网页内容的索引
creating an index of all of the content
或分析整个网络的链接结构
of the web or analyzing the link
structure of the entire web in order to
以便识别出最重要的页面或
identify the most important pages or the
最权威的页面，正如大家知道的那样
most authoritative pages as you know the
那时，整个网络甚至有
whole web is what's even in those days
数十TB的数据，构建
tens of terabytes of data building index
网络索引基本上等于
of the web is basically equivalent to a
跑遍所有的数据
sort running sort of the entire data
大家知道，这些相当
sort you know ones like reasonably
耗时，还有对整个内容进行排序
expensive and to run a sort on the
就像我一直用
entire content to the way I've been a
单台电脑那样
single computer
要花多长时间，但，你知道
how long would have taken but you know
那（可能是）几周，几个月或几年，甚至更多
it's weeks or months or years or
Google当时是
something so Google the time was
极其渴望能
desperate to be able to run giant
在数以千计的计算机上进行巨型数据计算
computations on giant data on thousands
以便
of computers in order that the
计算可以快速完成
computations could finish rapidly it's
对他们来说购买大量计算机是值得的
worth it to them to buy lots of
那样他们的工程师
computers so that their engineers
就不必浪费很多时间
wouldn't have to spend a lot of time
在看报纸或看其他东西上
reading the newspaper or something
在等待他们的大型计算任务完成时
waiting for their big compute jobs to
所以，有一段时间，他们让他们的
finish and so for a while they had their
聪明的工程师，手写
clever engineer or sort of handwrite you
如果你需要写一个网站
know if you needed to write a web
索引器或某种Lincoln支出
indexer or some sort of Lincoln outlay a
眨眼分析工具
blink analysis tool you know Google
Google买了电脑，他们那时说
bought the computers and they say here
工程师确实会写
engineers you know do write but never
但他们从不写你在电脑上喜欢的任何软件
whatever software you like on these
computers and you know they would
他们费力写那种一次性的
laborious ly write the sort of one-off
手动咬合的软件
manually bitten software to take
来入手他们正在解决的任何问题
whatever problem they were working on
所以以某种方式将其分包到大量
and so to somehow farm it out to a lot
电脑上，管理
of computers and organize that
运算，再取回数据，如果你
computation and get the data back if you
只雇用熟练分布式系统专家的工程师
only hire engineers who are skilled
就够了
distributed systems experts maybe that's
尽管即使那样也很
ok although even then it's probably very
浪费工程任务量，但他们
wasteful of engineering effort but they
想雇用有其他方面特长的人
wanted to hire people who were skilled
不一定是
at something else and not necessarily
想把所有时间花在
engineers who wanted to spend all their
编写分布式系统软件的工程师
time writing distributed system software
他们实际上需要某种
so they really needed some kind of
框架，那将很容易
framework that would make it easy to
让他们的工程师
just have their engineers write the kind
写出他们想做的任何分析的内容
of guts of whatever analysis they wanted
诸如排序算法、网络索引
to do like the sort algorithm or a web
链接分析器或其他任何的东西
index or link analyzer or whatever just
就写写那个应用程序的内容
write the guts of that application and
但无法在数千个电脑上运行它
not be able to run it on a thousands of
不用考虑
computers without worrying about the
如何在数千台计算机上分发任务的详细信息
details of how to spread the work over
the thousands of computers how to
如何组织所有的数据移动也是必需（考虑）的
organize whatever data movement was
如何应对不可避免的错误
required how to cope with the inevitable
于是他们找寻
failures so they were looking for a
易于使用的框架
framework that would make it easy for
让非专家也能够撰写和
non specialists to be able to write and
运行巨型分布式计算
run giant distributed computations and
这就是MapReduce的全部意义
so that's what MapReduce is all about
设计思想是程序员只
and the idea is that the programmer just
编写应用程序，设计师
write the application designer
分布式计算的使用者
consumer of this distributed computation
我就能写简单的Map
I'm just be able to write a simple Map
函数和简单的Reduce函数
function and a simple Reduce function
即使不知道任何分布式相关的内容
that don't know anything about
MapReduce框架
distribution and the MapReduce framework
会处理剩下的
would take care of everything else so an
什么是MapReduce的抽象视图
abstract view of how what MapReduce is
取决于它启动时是否假设
up to is it starts by assuming that
有一些输入，这些输入
there's some input and the input is
以某种方式被分成一堆
split up into some a whole bunch of
不同的文件或块
different files or chunks in some way so
我们假设
we're imagining that no yeah you know
输入文件一，放入文件二，依此类推
input file one and put file two etc you
这些输入也许是
know these inputs are maybe you know web
从网上抓取的网页或更
pages crawled from the web or more
可能是包含了许多网站的大文件
likely sort of big files that contain
每个都包含许多
many web each of which contains many web
从网上抓取的网页文件
files crawled from the web all right and
MapReduce启动的方式
the way MapReduce
是你要查找Map函数
starts is that you're to find a Map
MapReduce框架
function and the MapReduce framework is
会在每个输入文件上运行Map函数
gonna run your Map function on each of
当然可以
the input files and of course you can
这里我们可以看到一些明显的可用的并行
see here there's some obvious
可以并行地运行Maps
parallelism available can run the Maps
每个Map
in parallel so the each of these Map
函数只关注输入和输出
functions only looks as this input and
produces output the output that a Map
Map函数输出列表
function is required to produce is a
它将文件作为输入
list you know it takes a file as input
该文件是输入数据的一部分
and the file is some fraction of the
它生成一个key value对列表
input data and it produces a list of key
用做输出，Map函数
value pairs as output the Map function
例如，假设，我们
and so for example let's suppose we're
在编写最简单的MapReduce示例
writing the simplest possible MapReduce
单词计数，MapReduce的任务目标
example a word count MapReduce job goal
是计算每个单词出现的次数
is to count the number of occurrences of
你的Map函数可能
each word so your Map function might
emit key value对，其中key是
emit key value pairs where the key is
单词而value是1
the word and the value is just one so
对于c的每个单词，Map
for every word at c so then this Map
函数会将输入分割成
function will split the input up into
单词或随处可见
words or everywhere ditzies
它emit该单词作为key，并把1作为value
it emits that word as the key and 1 as
然后再进行整体计算
the value and then later on will count
得出最终输出
up all those ones in order to get the
也许输入1中
final output so you know maybe input 1
有单词a
has the word
和单词b
a in it and the word B in it and so the
Map的输出将会是
output the Map is going to produce is
key a value 1，key b value 1
key a value one key b value one maybe
也许第二个Map通信是一个文件
the second Map communication sees a file
其中只有一个b
that has a b in it and nothing else so
输出则是b 1
it's going to implement output b1 maybe
也许第三个输入中有一个a和一个c
this third input has an a in it and a c
我们在所有输入文件上运行Map
in it alright so we run all these Maps
得到一个中间量
on all the input files and we get this
这篇论文中叫做
intermediate with the paper calls
中间输出
intermediate output which is for every
每个Map用一组key value对作为输出
Map a set of key value pairs as output
第二阶段的计算
then the second stage of the computation
是运行Reduces，想法是
is to run the Reduces and the idea is
MapReduce框架收集
that the MapReduce framework collects
每个key词的所有Map的所有实例
together all instances from all Maps of
所以MapReduce框架
each key word so the MapReduce framework
会收集所有a的（Map实例）
is going to collect together all of the
从每个Map中
as you know from every Map every key
每个key为a的key value对
value pair whose key was a it's gonna
全部都会被收集并供
take collect them all and hand them to
程序员调用
one call of the programmer to find
以便寻找Reduce函数
Reduce function and then it's gonna take
然后是所有的b，收集在一起
all the bs and collect them together of
当然，需要真正的收集
course you know requires a real
因为它们是key b的不同的实例
collection because they were different
instances of key b were produced by
是由不同计算机上的不同Map生成的
different indications of Map on
所以我们不讨论
different computers so we're not talking
数据移动，我，我们要
about data movement I'm so we're gonna
收集所有b keys，把他们给
collect all the b keys and hand them to
另一个Reduce调用
a different call to Reduce that has all
那把所有的b keys作为参数
of the b keys as its arguments and same
c也一样
as c so there's going to be the
MapReduce框架给每个key安排了一个Reduce调用
MapReduce framework will arrange for one
这些key
call to Reduce for every key that
出现在我们这些简单计数示例的每个数学输出中
occurred in any of the math output and
you know for our sort of silly word
所有这些Reduce必须
count example all these Reduces have to
做或其中任何一个必须做的，就只是
do or any one of them has to do is just
计算传递给它的项目数
count the number of items passed to it
甚至不用看具体的项目
doesn't even have to look at the items
因为它知道每个都是
because it knows that each of them is
单词，都负责加1，即value
the word is responsible for plus one is
你不必看我们刚刚计数的这些value
the value you don't have to look at
those ones we've just count
所以这个Reduce将输出一个a
so this Reduce is going to produce a and
然后是它的输入数量，这个Reduce
then the count of its inputs this Reduce
它会生成与之关联的key
it's going to produce the key associated
然后计算其value
with it and then count of its values
也是2，这是一个
which is also two so this is what a
典型的看起来高级别的MapReduce任务
typical MapReduce job looks like the
为了完整性
high level just for completeness the
一些术语
well some a little bit of terminology
这整个计算称为作业（job）
the whole computation is called the job
MapReduce的每个调用都称为一个任务（task）
any one invocation of MapReduce is called
我们有整个作业
a task so we have the entire job and
它由一堆数学任务组成
it's made up of a bunch of math tasks
然后是一堆生成的任务
and then a bunch of produced tasks so
这是单词计数的一个例子
it's an example for this word count you
大家知道Map和Reduce
know the what the Map and Reduce
函数长什么样
functions would look like the Map
Map函数用key和value作为参数
function takes a key and a value as
我们现在讨论的函数
arguments and now we're talking about
是用普通的编程语言写的
functions like written in an ordinary
诸如C ++或Java或其他各种语言
programming language like C++ or Java or
这使得程序员和
so this is just code
普通人都可以写这些函数
people ordinary people can write what a
字数统计Map函数可以做的是分割
Map function for word count would do is
k是文件名
split the the k is the file name which
通常会被忽略，我们真正在意的是
typically is ignored we really care what
文件名，而v是
the file name was and the v is the
该Map输入文件的内容，v
content of this Maps input file so v is
包含了所有的文本
you know just contains all this text
我们将把v分割成单词
we're gonna split v into words and then
每个词
for each word
我们都会emit，emit需要两个参数
we're just gonna emit and emit takes two
emit，只调用Map，
arguments emit you know call only Map can
make emit provided by the MapReduce
emit，只调用Map，
可以做由MapReduce框架提供的emit
我们生成的框架
framework we get to produce we hand emit
我们给emit传递一个key（也就是该单词）
a key which is the word and a value
和一个value（也就是字符串'1'）
which is the string one so that's it for
这就是Map函数和字数统计的Map函数
the Map function and a word count Map
MapReduce从字面上看
function and MapReduce literally it
可能就这么简单
could be this simple
有希望做一些..
so there's sort of promise to make the
这个Map函数并不知道
and you know this Map function doesn't
任何分布式和
know anything about distribution or
多台计算机或...事实上我们需要
multiple computers or the fact we need
我们需要跨网络移动数据
we need to move data across the network
或谁知道的什么
or who knows what
这非常简单明了
this is extremely straightforward and
字数统计的Reduce函数
the Reduce function for a word count the
Reduce被调用，记住，
Reduce is called with you know remember
每个Reduce都会和所有有给定key的实例一起被调用
each Reduce is called with sort of all
the instances of a given key and the
MapReduce框架调用Reduce
MapReduce framework calls Reduce with
同时调用其负责的key
the key that it's responsible for and a
produced associated with that key the
key是单词，而value全是1
key is the word the values are all ones
这里我们不关心他们，我们只是
we don't like here about them we only
关心他们有多少
care about how many they were and so
Reduce有它自己的emit函数
Reduce has its own emit function that
该函数只emit一个value
just takes a value to be emitted as the
作为最终输出，作为这个key的value
final output as the value for the this
我们要emit这个数字的长度
key so we're gonna emit a length of
这个数组，这就是关于，有..是..
this array so this is all about as
MapReduce中的最简单的Reduce函数的全部
simplest Reduce functions have are and
非常简单
in MapReduce namely extremely simple
不需要容错知识
and requiring no knowledge about fault
或其他任何知识
tolerance or anything else alright any
对基本框架有什么疑惑吗
questions about the basic framework yes
[音乐]
[Music]
你的意思是你可以给出Reduce的输出
you mean can you feed the output of the
有点..哦是..哦是..
Reduces sort of oh yes oh yes in in in
在现实生活中可以
in real life all right
在现实生活中这是日常的
in real life it is routine among
MapReduce用户定义一个
MapReduce users to you know define a
MapReduce作业，需要一些输入和
MapReduce job that took some inputs and
生成一些输出
produce some outputs and then have a
第二个MapReduce作业
second MapReduce job you know you're
做一些非常复杂的多阶段
doing some very complicated multistage
分析或迭代算法
analysis or iterative algorithm like
例如PageRank
PageRank for example which is the
Google所用的评估算法
algorithm Google uses to sort of
估测不同的网页有多重要或多有影响力
estimate how important or influential
different webpages are that's an
迭代算法是渐进的
iterative algorithm is sort of gradually
收敛于答案
converges on an answer and if you
如果你用MapReduce实现
implement in MapReduce which I think
我想他们最初就是这样
they originally did you have to run the
你必须多次运行MapReduce作业
MapReduce job multiple times and the
每个输出都是
output of each one is sort of you know
更新的网页列表
list of webpages with an updated sort of
更新的内容是每个网页的价值，权重或重要性
value or weight or importance for each
得到一个输出
webpage so it was routine to take this
并用它作为另一个MapReduce作业的输入是很日常的
output and then use it as the input to
哦，是的，是的
another MapReduce job oh yeah well yeah
你需要根据输出设定一些内容
you need to sort of set things up the
你需要评估Reduce函数
output you need to rate the Reduce
在某种程度上了解
function sort of in the knowledge that
哦，我需要按一定格式或信息
oh I need to produce data that's in the
所需生成数据
format or as the information required
给下一个MapReduce作业，我的意思是这
for the next MapReduce job I mean this
实际上引出了一些
actually brings up a little bit of a
MapReduce框架的缺点
shortcoming in the MapReduce framework
这很棒，如果你..
which is it's great if you are if the
如果你需要运行的算法很容易
algorithm you need to run is easily
表达成数学形式，随后是
expressible as a math followed by this
按key对数据进行洗牌
sort of shuffling of the data by key
接着是Reduce，仅此而已
followed by a Reduce and that's it
我的MapReduce有极好的算法
My MapReduce is fantastic for algorithms
可以以这种形式展示
that can be cast in that form and we're
此外我们...每个Map都必须
furthermore each of the Maps has to be
完全独立
completely independent and
必须是纯函数性的
are required to be functional pure
函数性函数
functional functions that just look at
只需看看他们的参数，仅此而已
their arguments and nothing else
那就像一个限制
you know that's like it's a restriction
事实证明，很多人想要
and it turns out that many people want
运行更长的管道
to run much longer pipelines that
涉及很多很多不同种类的
involve lots and lots of different kinds
处理过程，并与MapReduce一起使用
of processing and with MapReduce you
你不得不拼装
have to sort of cobble that together
多个MapReduce，不同的
from multiple MapReduce distinct
MapReduce作业和更高级的系统
MapReduce jobs and more advanced systems
这些我们将在后面讨论
which we will talk about later in the
这节课更擅长让你
course are much better at allowing you
指定完整的计算管道
to specify the complete pipeline of
他们会做优化
computations and they'll do optimization
框架实现了所有
you know the framework realizes all the
你要做的事情和组织
stuff you have to do and organize much
更复杂有效地优化
more complicated efficiently optimize
更复杂的计算
much more complicated computations
从程序员的角度来看
from the programmers point of view it's
只是Map和Reduce，从我们的角度来看
just about Map and Reduce from our point
这将关乎
of view it's going to be about the
任务进程和任务服务器
worker processes and the worker servers
他们是MapReduce框架的一部分
that that are they're part of MapReduce
除其他情况外
framework that among many other things
调用Map和Reduce函数
call the Map and Reduce functions so
是的，从我们的角度来看，我们比较关心
yeah from our point of view we care a
环境框架是如何组织这些的
lot about how this is organized by the
surrounding framework this is sort of
从程序员的角度来看
the programmers view with all the
所有分发的内容都弄完了
distributive stuff stripped out yes
对不起，我得..再说一遍，哦，你的意思是
sorry I gotta say it again oh you mean
实时数据是什么情况
where does the immediate data go okay so
现在有两个问题，一个是当你
there's two questions one is when you
调用Map，数据会发生什么变化，
call a Map what happens to the data and
另一个问题是函数怎样运行
the other is where the functions run so
实际答案是，首先
the actual answer is that first where
这些东西是如何运行
the stuffs run there's a number of say
有许多，比如一千台服务器，实际上
a thousand servers um actually the right
这里需要关注的内容是在这篇论文里找出一个
thing to look at here is figure one in
在这个基础上，现实世界里
the paper sitting underneath this in the
有许多
real world there's some big collection
服务器集群，我们称它们为
of servers and we'll call them maybe
工作服务器或工作站
worker servers or workers and there's
同时也有单台master服务器
also a single master server that's
来管理整个计算过程
organizing the whole computation and
这时发生的情况是master
what's going on here is the master
服务器知道有
server for know knows that there's some
许多输入文件
number of input files you know five
如五千个输入文件
thousand input files and it farms out in
通过Map分包到不同的worker服务器
vacations of Map to the different
它将消息发送给
workers so it'll send a message to
worker服务器，说请运行吧
worker sever saying please run you know
Map函数，在某某输入文件上
this Map function on such-and-such an
接着worker函数
input file and then the worker function
MapReduce的一部分
which is you know part of MapReduce and
非常了解MapReduce
knows all about MapReduce well then
会读取文件，读取输入，无论是什么
read the file read the input whatever
无论是哪个，输入文件，然后调用Map函数
whichever input file and call this Map
同时以文件名value作为其函数参数
function with the file name value as its
然后工作进程
arguments then that worker process will
会进行内部实现
implement what implements in it and
每次Map调用emit
every time the Map calls emit the worker
工作进程会将这些数据写到本地磁盘的文件
process will write this data to files on
Map emits是什么情况呢
the local disk so what happens to Map
它们在
emits and is they produce files on the
在Map worker服务器的本地磁盘上生成文件
Map workers local disk that are
累计worker上的Map生成的所有的key和value
accumulating all the keys and values
produced by the Maps run on that worker
在Map阶段结束时
so at the end of the Maps phase what
留给我们的就是那些worker机器
we're left with is all those worker
每台机器有
machines each of which has the output of
一些在上面运行的Map
some of whatever Maps were run on that
worker机器上，然后MapReduce
worker machine then the MapReduce
worker安排将数据移到
workers arrange to move the data to
它需要的地方
where it's going to be needed for the
供Reduce调用
Reduces so and since and a you know in a
在典型的大型计算中
typical big computation you know this
Reduce指令需要
this Reduce indication is going to need
所有提到了key a的Map输出
all Map output that
那会变成事实的
mentioned the key a but it's gonna turn
这是一个简单的例子
out you know this is a simple example
但一般来说，每个Map
but probably in general every single Map
指令会生成很多
indication will have produce lots of
key，包括a的某些实例
keys including some instances of key a
所以通常，在我们
so typically in order before we can even
运行MapReduce框架的Reduce函数之前
run this Reduce function the MapReduce
是MapReduce worker
framework that is the MapReduce worker
在我们数千台服务器中的一台上运行
running on one of our thousand servers
将不得不去与
is going to have to go talk to every
上千个服务器中的另外的每个单个服务器进行通信
single other of the thousand servers and
说，看，我要运行Reduce
say look you know I'm gonna run the
获取key a，请看一下
Reduce for key a please look at the
存储在你的磁盘上的中间Map输出
intermediate Map output stored in your
完成 key a 的所有实例
disk and finish out all of the instances
把他们通过网络发送给我
of key a and send them over the network
Reduce worker将执行指令
to me so the Reduce worker is going to
它会从每个worker获取
do that it's going to fetch from every
key的所有实例
worker all of the instances of the key
它负责
that it's responsible for that the
master让它去做的事
master has told it to be responsible for
一旦它收集完所有数据
and once it's collected all of that data
它就可以调用Reduce
then it can call Reduce and the Reduce
Reduce函数本身调用Reduce emit
function itself calls Reduce emit which
emit与其中的Map不同
is different from the Map in it and what
Reduces emit 把输出写到
Reduces emit does is writes the output
谷歌使用的集群文件服务中的文件里
to a file in a cluster file service that
这里有些东西
Google uses so here's something I
我还没提过，我没有提到
haven't mentioned I haven't mentioned
输入所在的位置以及
where the input lives and where the
输出所在的位置，他们都在文件里，因为
output lives they're both files because
一段输入，我们需要灵活性
any piece of input we want the
需要它能在任何worker服务器上读取任意一段输入
flexibility to be able to read any piece
也就是
of input on any worker server that means
我们需要某种网络文件系统
we need some kind of network file system
存储输入数据
to store the input data and so indeed
实际上这篇论文谈到了这个，即
the paper talks about this thing called
GFS或Google文件系统，而GFS是
GFS or Google file system and GFS is a
集群文件系统，GFS实际上
cluster file system and GFS actually
在完全相同的一组worker上运行
runs on exactly the same set of workers
这些worker servers运行MapReduce
that worker servers that run MapReduce
输入GFS只是自动...
and the input GFS just automatically
这是一个你能读取我的文件的文件系统
when you you know it's a file system you
can read in my files it just
GFS会自动拆分你的任何大文件
automatically splits up any big file you
将其存储在跨服务器和最大64MB的块上
store on it across lots of servers and
如果你写
64 megabyte chunks so if you write
如果你查看了10 TB的已爬
if you view of ten terabytes of crawled
网页内容，你只需把他们写到
web page contents and you just write
GFS，甚至作为一个大文件
them to GFS even as a single big file
GFS将自动把大数据拆分成64 KB的块
GFS will automatically split that vast
amount of data up into 64 kilobyte
使其均匀地分布在所有
chunks distributed evenly over all of
GFS服务器上，也就是说
the GFS servers which is to say all the
Google提供的所有服务器都可以用
servers that Google has available and
这非常美妙，这正是我们需要的
that's fantastic that's just what we
如果我们接下来要运行MapReduce任务
need if we then want to run a MapReduce
抓取的整个网站作为输入
job that takes the entire crawled web as
数据均匀分割后
input the data is already stored in a
存储在所有的跨服务器上了
way that split up evenly across all the
这意味着
servers and so that means that the Map
Map worker，我们要启动
workers you know we're gonna launch you
我们有一千台服务器
know if we have a thousand servers we're
我们要启动一千个Map  worker
gonna launch a thousand Map workers each
每个输入数据读取，1000秒
reading one 1000s at the input data and
他们可以并行地读取
they're going to be able to read the
一千个GFS文件服务器里的数据
data in parallel from a thousand GFS
总的庞大的
file servers thus getting now tremendous
读取吞吐量
total read throughput you know the read
一千台服务器上的
throughput up a thousand servers
你可能在想也许Google
so so are you thinking maybe that Google
有一组物理机器
has one set of physical machines among
介于GFS和一组单独运行MapReduce任务的物理机器之间
GFS and a separate set of physical
介于GFS和一组单独运行MapReduce作业的物理机器之间
machines that run MapReduce jobs okay
对，所以问题是
right so the question is what does this
这里的箭头实际上涉及了什么内容
arrow here actually involve and the
答案是实际上那是随着时间改变的
answer that actually it sort of changed
自Google
over the years as Google's
涉足这个系统后
involve this system but you know what
在一般情况下，如果我们有
this in those general case if we have
大文件存储在某个大网络文件系统中
big files stored in some big Network
像GFS
file system like you know it's like GFS
可能有点像你在Athena上使用过的AFS
is a bit like AFS you might have used on
你去跟某些数据集通信
Athena where you go talk to some
你的数据在集群服务器里被拆分
collection and your data split over a big
你必须在网络上和那些服务器通信
collection of servers you have to go talk
to those servers over the network to
去检索你的数据，在那种情况下
retrieve your data in that case what
该箭头可能代表的是Map
this arrow might represent is the Map
MapReduce任务进程必须关闭
MapReduce worker process has to go off
跨网通信到
and talk across the network to the
正确的GFS服务器上，或者
correct GFS server or maybe servers that
存储部分输入的服务器
store it's part of the input and fetch
通过网络获取，连接到MapReduce
it over the network to the MapReduce
worker机器，传递Map
worker machine in order to pass the Map
那当然是最一般的情况
and that's certainly the most general
以上就是MapReduce最终是
case and that was eventually how
如何工作的
MapReduce actually worked in the world
在这篇论文里面，如果你做了
of this paper though and and if you did
那里有很多网络通信
that that's a lot of network
你通信10TB的数据
communication are you talking about ten
我们就从他们的数据中心网络移动了10TB
terabytes of data and we have moved 10
terabytes across their data center
数据中心
network which you know data center
网络是每秒GB级的
networks wanting gigabits per second but
但仍然需要很多时间
it's still a lot of time to move tens of
去移动数十TB的数据，为了尝试...
terabytes of data in order to try to and
实际上在这篇2004年的论文中
indeed in the world of this paper in
他们最具约束力的瓶颈
2004 the most constraining bottleneck in
是MapReduce系统中的网络吞吐量
their MapReduce system was Network
因为它们要在网络上运行
throughput because they were running on
如果你深读了
a network if you sort of read as far as
评估部分
the evaluation section their network
他们的网络，有成千上万的
their network as was they had thousands
机器
of machines
他们会集成机器
whatever and they would collect machines
他们会插入机器
they would plug machines and you know
机器的每个机架
each rack of machines and you know an
机架的以太网交换机或者其他
Ethernet switch for that rack or
他们全部
something but then you know they all
需要互相通信
need to talk to each other but there was
还有路由以太网交换机
a route Ethernet switch that all of the
所有的网络交换机要与之通信
Rackies are net switches talked to and
如果你只是
this one and you know so if you just
选择一些MapReduce worker和一些GFS服务器
pick some MapReduce worker and some GFS
可能最少是
server you know chances are at least
他们之间必须跨通信的时间的一半
half the time the communication between
them has to pass through this one
这一个不会改变他们的路线
wouldn't switch their routes which had
仅占总吞吐量的一部分
only some amount of total throughput
我忘了
which I forget you know some number of
每秒几GB，我忘记具体的数据了
gigabits per second and I forget the
但是当我做除法时
number well but when I did the division
被除数是
that is divided up to the total
路线中可用的总吞吐量
throughput available in the routes which
他们在这篇论文实验中使用的大约是2000台服务器
by the roughly 2000 servers that they
used in the papers experiments what I
我得到的结论是
got was that each machine share of the
路由交换机或整个网络
route switch or of the total network
容量的每台机器分量仅为每秒50Mb
capacity was only 50 megabits per second
在他们的设置中
per second in their setup 50 megabits
每台机器每秒50Mb
per second per machine and then might
看起来好像是很多50Mb
seem like a lot 50 megabits gosh
但实际上
millions and millions but it's actually
只有非常小的一部分能比肩磁盘运行的速度
quite small compared to how fast disks
或者CPU运行的速度
run or CPUs run and so this with their
他们的网络，每秒50Mb
network this 50 megabits per second was
有一个巨大的限制，所以他们
like a tremendous limit and so they
脑中坚定要
really stood on their heads in the
在论文中提到的设计中
design described in the paper to avoid
避免使用网络
using the network and they played a
他们使用了一堆技巧
bunch of tricks to avoid sending stuff
尽一切可能避免在网络上发送东西
over the network when they possibly
其中之一是他们...
could avoid it one of them was they
他们在同一组机器中使用gfs服务器和
would they ran the gfs servers and the
MapReduce workers
MapReduce workers on the same set of
他们有一千台机器
machines so they have a thousand
运行GFS
machines they'd run GFS they implement
他们在一千台机器实现GFS服务
their GFS service on that thousand
并在同一千台机器上运行MapReduce
machines and run MapReduce on the same
thousand machines and then when the
master分拆Map任务
master was splitting up the Map work and
分包到不同的worker服务器
sort of farming it out to different
那很智能
workers it would cleverly when it was
当它即将运行Map时
about to run the Map that was going to
map读取输入文件1
read from input file one it would figure
它会从GFS中找出来哪个服务器
out from GFS which server actually holds
的本地磁盘中有输入文件1
input file one on its local disk and it
它将把输入文件发送给Map
would send the Map for that input file
到同一机器上的MapReduce软件
to the MapReduce software on the same
因此默认情况下此箭头
machine so that by default this arrow
实际上是读取
was actually local local read from the
本地磁盘，并且不涉及
local disk and did not involve the
网络，这取决于
network and you know depending on
故障或负载或其他
failures or load or whatever that
也不可能总是那样做，但几乎所有
couldn't always do that but almost all
Map都会在相同的机器上运行
the Maps would be run on the very same
和存储数据，从而节省
machine and stored the data thus saving
大量时间
them vast amount of time that they would
而如果在网络中移动输入，这些时间则是必须要等待的
otherwise had to wait to move the input
他们玩的下一个窍门是
data across the network the next trick
我提过的，Map
they played is that Map as I mentioned
在输出存储到机器的本地磁盘之前
before stores this output on the local
你就运行Map
disk of the machine that you run the Map
又一次，存储Map的输出
on so again storing the output of the
不需要网络通信
Map does not require network
他不是实时
communication he's not immediately
因为输出存储在了磁盘中
because the output stored in the disk
但是我们肯定知道，不管怎样，
however we know for sure that one way or
为了全部分组
another in order to group together all
按照MapReduce定义的方式
of you know by the way the MapReduce is
为了把与给定key关联的所有的value全部分组
defined in order to group together all
of the values associated with the given
并将其传递给单个调用
key and pass them to a single invocation
在某些机器上生成（数据），这将
to produce on some machine this is going
需要网络通讯
to require network communication we're
我们想要获取
gonna you know we want to need to fetch
所有这些，把他们给到单台
all these and give them a single
必须在网络上移动的机器
machine that have to be moved across the
所以这个洗牌
network and so this shuffle this
keys的这种移动方式
movement of the keys from its kind of
最初按行存储在同一台运行Map的机器上的
originally stored by row and on the same
我们实际上需要它们
machine that ran the Map we need them
按列存储在
essentially to be stored on by column on
机器上
the machine that's going to be
负责Reduce
responsible for Reduce this
这种将行存储的变为
transformation of row storage
列存储的转换本质上称为
essentially column storage is called the
这篇论文称为，洗牌。它确实很需要
paper calls a shuffle and it really that
在网络上移动的每条数据
required moving every piece of data
通过Map生成传到
across the network from the Map that
Reduce
produced it to the Reduce that would
还需要它（洗牌），现在它像
need it and now it's like the expensive
是MapReduce代价最大的一部分
part of the MapReduce yeah
你是对的，你可以想象一个不同的
you're right you can imagine a different
定义，在里面你有更多的
definition in which you have a more kind
Reduce流。我不知道
of streaming Reduce I don't know I
我还没仔细想过这个
haven't thought this through I don't
我不知道为什么...那是否可行
know why whether that would be feasible
当然，至于程序员界面而言
or not certainly as far as programmer
目标
interface like if the goal their
他们的第一目标是否确实是能够
number-one goal really was to be able to
易于编程的
make it easy to program by people who
对于只是不知道系统发生了什么的人来说
just had no idea of what was going on in
可能是，你知道的
the system so it may be that you know
小缺陷
this speck this is really the way Reduce
这正是Reduce函数的样子
functions look and you know in C++ or
在C ++或像这样的流版
something like a streaming version of
现在看起来的样子
this is now starting to look I don't
我不知道它究竟是啥样
know how it look probably not this
或许没这么简单
simple but you know maybe it could be
也许可以用那种方式做
done that way and indeed many modern
实际上很多现代系统...
systems people got a lot more
人们对现代事物了解更多
sophisticated with modern things that
如MapReduce的后继者们
are the successors the MapReduce and
他们确实经常涉及处理
they do indeed involve processing
数据流，而不是这些
streams of data often rather than this
批处理的方法
very batch approach there is a batch
从某种意义上说，有一种批处理方法
approach in the sense that we wait until
我们要一直等待所有数据获取完时才能处理
we get all the data and then we process
因此，首先，你必须
it so first of all that you then have to
有一个有限输入的概念
have a notion of finite inputs right
现代系统通常确实可以处理流
modern systems often do indeed you
也能够
streams and and are able to take
充分利用MapReduce的效率
advantage of some efficiencies do that
好吧，这就是洗牌的重点
MapReduce okay so this is the point at
which this shuffle is where all the
所有的网络路线是哪里发生的
network traffic happens this can
这实际上可能有海量数据
actually be a vast amount of data so if
如果你想要排序，如果你在
you think about sort if you're sorting
排序的输出和输入有相同的大小
the the output of the sort has the same
size as the input to the sort so that
也就是
means that if you're you know if your
如果你的输入是10 TB的数据
input is 10 terabytes of data and you're
你在做排序，你在这里要
running a sort you're moving 10
跨网络移动10TB的数据
terabytes of data across a network at
你的输出也将是10TB
this point and your output will also be
这是量非常大的数据
10 terabytes and so this is quite a lot
他们确实来自任意的
of data and then indeed it is from any
MapReduce作业，尽管不是全部的
MapReduce jobs although not all there's
确实有些，在这些阶段，很大程度上减少数据量
some that significantly Reduce the
amount of data at these stages somebody
有人提到，哦，如果你想把
mentioned Oh what if you want to feed
Reduce 的输出传给另一个
the output of Reduce into another
MapReduce作业，的确如此，那是
MapReduce job and indeed that was often
人们想做的事
what people wanted to do and
如果Reduce的输出可能
in case the output of the Reduce might
像排序或网站一样巨大
be enormous like for sort or web and
10TB输入生成的输出
mixing the output of the produces on ten
Reduces的输出
terabytes of input the output of the
也会是10TB
Reduces again gonna be ten terabytes so
Reduce的输出也会保存
the output of the Reduce is also stored
在GFS里，系统将...
on GFS and the system would you know
Reduce只会生成这些key
Reduce would just produce these key
value对，但MapReduce框架
value pairs but the MapReduce framework
会把它们收集起来并写入
would gather them up and write them into
GFS上的巨型文件里
giant files on GFS and so there was
另一轮网络通讯
another round of network communication
需要把每个Reduce的输出
required to get the output of each
弄到需要存储Reduce的GFS服务器上
Reduce to the GFS server that needed to
因为你可能
store that Reduce and because you might
认为他们也许用了相同的技巧
think that they could have played the
（就是）把输出
same trick with the output of storing
存在GFS服务器上
the output on the GFS server that
同时运行了 MapReduce worker
happened to run the MapReduce worker
运行了 Reduce，也许他们确实那样做了
that ran the Reduce and maybe they did
但是由于GFS以及
do that but because GFS as well as
拆分数据以提高性能
splitting data for performance also
也为容错保留两三份副本
keeps two or three copies for fault
这意味着无论你
tolerance that means no matter what you
需要什么去写一份数据备份
need to write one copy of the data
跨网络连接到其他服务器
across a network to a different server
有很多网络通信
so there's a lot of network
这儿就有一大堆
communication here and a bunch here also
而我是这个网络通信
and I was this network communication
在2004年，那确实限制了MapReduce的吞吐量
that really limited the throughput in
MapReduce
2020年，因为网络
in 2004 in 2020 because this network
布局是一个很大的限制性因素
arrangement was such a limiting factor
很多人们想做的事情
for so many things people wanted to do
在数据中心，现代数据中心
in datacenters modern data center
网络从根本上讲要比过去快很多
networks are a lot faster at the root
所以大家知道
than this was and so you know one
你现在可能会看到的典型的数据中心网络
typical data center network you might
实际上有很多根
see today actually has many root instead
而不是，所有数据要经过的单个根交换机
of a single root switch that everything
你可能有..
has to go through you might have you
许多根交换机,每个机架
know many root switches and each rack
交换机与每个这种备份根交换机相连
switch has a connection to each of these
sort of replicated root switches and the
流量在根交换机之间分配
traffic is split up among the root
现代数据中心网络
switches so modern data center networks
具有更大的网络吞吐量
have far more network throughput and
因为，我认为，实际上，现代
because of that actually modern I think
Google在几年前就开始停止使用MapReduce
Google sort of stopped using MapReduce a
但在他们停止使用之前
few years ago but before they stopped
现代MapReduce
using it the modern MapReduce actually
已不再试图在同一机器上运行Map
no longer tried to run the Maps on the
当数据在存储时
same machine as the data stored on they
很高兴能从任何地方对数据进行投票
were happy to vote the data from
因为他们认为
anywhere because they just assumed that
那样速度非常快，好了，我们
was extremely fast okay we're out of
没有更多的时间说MapReduce了
time for MapReduce
我们下周有一个lab
we have a lab due at the end of next
week
你可以自己在里面编写一些
in which you'll write your own somewhat
简化的MapReduce，请尽情耍
simplified MapReduce so have fun with
that
周四见
and see you on Thursday